

# **Victor Wang**

Software Engineer

#### About me

When I found a hobby in hiking, I finished the Inca Trail. When I found a market opportunity, I started a business. And when I created my first application, I found a passion for programming. I've gone from Business Development to Web Development after eight years of being a successful sales leader. As a developer, I apply the same level of focus, resourcefulness, and ambition to my work as I have with my accomplishments. I'm always seeking ways to improve and I'm hungry to learn more.

## Contact

(203) 848 - 9965

 $\bowtie$ 

mailbox.vmw@gmail.com

(0)

Philadelphia, PA

#### Links

in

victor-wang-14890753



v-wang



www.victorwang.me

## **Education**

General Assembly Software Engineering Immersive (Oct 2021 - Jan 2022)

Saint Joseph's University Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Biology (2008-2012)

- Achievement Award Scholarship
- United Scholars Grant
- New Member Educator of Sigma Phi Epsilon

# Skills / Languages

JavaScript

- HTML / CSS
- React.jsGit / GitHub
- Node.js

Express.js

API integrations

Heroku

- it / GitHub Mongoose
  - MongoDB

PostgresSQL

- CRM development
- Growth hacking
- Conversational Mandarin

# Projects - visit www.victorwang.me for all projects

#### The Daily Issue - React.js

Find issues for trending GitHub repositories and contribute to open-source projects. The Daily Issue is a web-based application that scrapes live data from GitHub in combination with retrieving repository information from the GitHub API.

#### Snow Scooper - MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js

Rough winter? Unable to shovel all that snow on your front porch? Snow Scooper is a mobile-friendly web app that helps connect neighbors who want to volunteer and help.

#### Chatter - Python, Django, React.js, PostgresSQL, WebSockets

Learning a new language? What better way to practice than to chat live with fluent speakers? Meet Chatter, a quick way to connect with fluent speakers through text. Learning a new language is hard, and learning how to speak conversationally can be even harder. Practice and hone your skills with Chatter and make new connections along the way.

# Experience

## Software Engineering Fellow General Assembly - Remote (Oct 2021 - Jan 2022)

Engineering Immersive program that includes over 400 hours of professional training over 12 weeks. Utilizes hands-on approach to design and build web applications with full CRUD functionality through Javascript, React, Express, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Python, Django.

#### Vice President, Partnerships

#### Peergrade Inc. - Boston, MA / Copenhagen, Denmark (Mar 2018 - Oct 2021)

- Built and lead the sales organization from the ground up and supported sales operations
- Increased monthly recurring revenue by 152% within one year (2018-2019)
- Lead the launch of Eduflow, a new SaaS training tool, at the end of 2019 and identified and secured early adopters
- Grew monthly active users from 4,000 to 239,000 since the launch of Eduflow

#### Vice President, Sales

### Swing Education - San Mateo, CA (Apr 2017 - Oct 2017)

- Secured school partners within 5-months and built a pipeline of roughly 600 partners
- Transitioned the organization to a new CRM and lead both deployment and implementation to help support initial efforts in marketing and sales automation
- Developed and lead a team of six contractors, from training to establishing sales strategy and standard operating procedures
- Attended conferences and began an aggressive events program to drive new and existing relationships

#### Vice President, Business Development

## The New York Code + Design Academy - New York, NY (Nov 2015 - Nov 2016)

- Created and launched Generation Code, an innovative computer science education program for public and private schools throughout the US
- Generated nearly \$200,000 in revenue within 4 months of launch
- Lead full partnership cycles including outreach, contract negotiations, execution and client services
- Determined strategic direction and identified key partnerships